# **Angel Po-Chen Chang**

1730 Carroll Street D1, Brooklyn 11213, NY · angelchang417@gmail.com · (917) 436-2497

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To earn a master's degree in computer science, and to become a top full stack web developer. I want to use my familiarity with the editorial process/mindset to better manage the relationship between engineers and content producers in digital media startups. I also want to build applications that better suit *writers*' needs, and that bolster the user experience for all clients.

# **SUMMARY OF SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS**

**Technical:** 

Microsoft Office, WordPress, CMS, Omniture, Google Analytics, workflow management, editorial process and planning, Adobe Photoshop, AP Style, SEO principles and practice, basic HTML and CSS, basic PHP object-oriented programming Languages:

English Mandarin French Dutch Taiwanese

- Excellent analytical and conceptual skills
- Hit over 20 million PVs with content last month
- Youngest writer on our entire creative team with 30+ content producers. Routinely in top 3 writers to receive bonuses each month
- Original content pieces regularly picked up and featured by major news aggregators

### **EDUCATION**

**New York University**, New York, NY Bachelor of Arts, Class of 2015 Double major in Journalism and French

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LittleThings.com, New York, NY

Original Content Producer, July 2015—present

• Curating, pitching and packaging viral human interest/social content for highly successful media startup/Facebook publisher

- Optimizing headlines and visuals for Facebook copy
- Developing, researching, and writing purely original content
- Pitching production and news ideas for our joint video production department
- Developing storytelling strategies to reflect brand's personality
- Prioritizing multiple multimedia projects in a fast-paced environment

#### **BBC Worldwide** (BBC Travel), New York, NY

Digital Editorial Intern, September 2014—May 2015

- Developed and wrote photo stories in partnership with National Geographic
- Moderated social engagement on Facebook and Twitter
- Produced weekly "Best of Travel" and "Most Popular" sections on homepage
- Produced videos in partnership with BBC's The Travel Show
- Produced themed slideshows, ranked stories on the homepage
- Monitored and analyzed site traffic and optimized headlines accordingly
- Conducted research for the intern project on the BBC's top social media influencers

# Complex Media (First We Feast), New York, NY

Digital Editorial Intern, May 28 2014—August 28, 2014

- Sourced and wrote news-oriented blog posts with multimedia
- Created slideshow galleries for stories
- Wrote news compilation posts, event roundups and guides
- Sourced and produced recipes
- Wrote longer feature-style stories that included infographics and videos

### amNewYork, New York, NY

Features Editorial Intern, June 2013—August 2013

- Worked closely with features editor to create content for the dining section
- Conducted interviews with recipe/cookbook authors, NYC chefs and restaurateurs
- Covered restaurant openings and thematic articles
- Wrote pieces on upcoming city food festivals and events
- Created editorial content for new food column
- Updated the weekly "health calendar" of city fitness events
- Wrote articles for the health and education sections

**Washington Square News** (NYU's daily student newspaper), New York, NY *Dining Editor*, January 2013—May 2013

- Managed a team of 15+ writers and contributors
- Oversaw weekly production and workflow, and generated story coverage
- Helped plan annual comprehensive dining guide